Elham Sallin-Barzegaran

Data Scientist - Msc in Computer Science

@ e.barzegaran@gmail.com

+41 79 918 33 31

Echandens, Switzerland



Professional Experience

Data Scientist II - Expedia Group

Revenue Performance Analytics: Rev+, Market Maker, Revenue Performance API

Aug 2021 - Present

9 Geneva, Switzerland

- Worked with multiple stakeholders from Commercial, Product, PRPM and Marketing to support Revenue Performance analytics.
- Designed and refined Rev Performance success metrics and reporting in collaboration with E4B finance, Commercial and Product team.
- Constructed Incrementality model for Rev+ and Market Maker using Casual Ransom Forest, basis of Rev Perf main success metric.
- Refrefresh and reconstructed Rev+ Rule-based segmentation pipeline.
 Additionally, built a behavioural segmentation model for Rev+ to specify user personas.
- Built and maintained several data pipeline and reporting dashboards for Rev Performance.

Postdoctoral Researcher - University of Fribourg Project: Functional networks of visual cortex

Jun 2019 - Mar 2021

♀ Fribourg, Switzerland

- New insights on brain functional networks in visual processing from high dimensional physiological data. Published in Plos Biology.
- Developped data pipelines including preprocessing, causality analysis, multivariate time series analysis, linear regression, clustering and factor analysis. The codes available in Python and Matlab.

Postdoctoral Researcher - Stanford University Project: Simulation framework for dimensionality reduction methods

math Jan 2018 - Jun 2019

♀ Stanford, United states

- Developed a realistic simulation framework for assessment and validation of analysis methods applied to high dimensional data (EEG).
 The Toolbox and dataset are available on Open Science Framework.
- New insights on cortical sources of visual acuities. Data processing pipeline included signal processing, dimensionality reduction and hypothesis testing. Published in Nature Scientific Reports.

Education

PhD in Neuroscience - University of Lausanne Project: Human Brain Rhythms

• Supported by Nano-Tera program, BodyPoweredSenSE project.

MSc in Computer Science - Sharif University of Technology Project focus: Analysis of complex networks

▼ Tehran, Iran

• Major in Artificial Intelligence

Personal Statement

With several years of experience as data scientist at Expedia Group and research in academia, I enjoy diving into complex data to extract patterns and insights that can be translated into practical solutions.

Skills

- Languages: English, French, Farsi
- Programmin languages: R, Python, Matlab, Pyspark, SQL
- Tableau
- Data Visualization in Python/Excel
- Statistical Analysis
- Knowledge of Machine Learning
- Time-Series Analysis
- Signal Processing
- Object Oriented Programming

More Information



LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elham-barzegaran-4a109242/



Publications

https://scholar.google.ch/citations?user=mQTnCWcAAAAJhl=en



Github - Academic Projects

https://github.com/EBarzegaran/



IEX - Expedia Analyses

iex.expedia.biz/
page/eg-insights/
spx-ax-revenue-performance-analyses

Achievements

- Awarded early postdoc mobility grant -Swiss National Science Foundation for a 1.5-year postdoc at Stanford university, Date: Jan 2018- June 2019.
- Published nine scientific articles in wellknown peer-reviewed scientific journals and presented in several international conferences.